Guide to the Arthur M. Schlesinger, Jr. papers, 1922-2007
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- Series IV: Research Files, 385866; 142 boxes
  - Subseries IV. A. Subject Files, 1950s-2000s; 385867; 73 boxes
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 385881
      - 1982, 385882 (Box 367, Folder 2)
      - 1983, 385883 (Box 367, Folder 3)
      - Centennial, 385884 (Box 367, Folder 4)
      - General, 385885 (Box 368, Folder 1-2)
    - American Heritage, 385886 (Box 368, Folder 3)
    - American historians, 385887 (Box 368, Folder 4)
    - American Historical Association, 385888
      - Russian dissidents, 385889 (Box 368, Folder 5)
      - General, 385890 (Box 368, Folder 6)
      - General, 385891 (Box 369, Folder 1)
    - Americans for Democratic Action, 385892
      - 1950s, 385893 (Box 369, Folder 2)
      - 1960s, 385894 (Box 369, Folder 3-4)
      - General, 385895 (Box 369, Folder 5-6)
    - Andrew Jackson (film script consultation), 385896 (Box 370, Folder 1)
    - Anti-communism, 385897 (Box 370, Folder 2)
    - Arthur M. Schlesinger Memorial Fund, 385898 (Box 370, Folder 3)
    - Arts and government, 385899 (Box 370, Folder 4)
    - Ascoli, Max, 385900 (Box 370, Folder 5)
    - Atomic bomb, 385901 (Box 370, Folder 6)
    - Authors Guild, 385902 (Box 370, Folder 7)
    - Bancroft, George, 385903 (Box 370, Folder 8)
    - Bay of Pigs, 385904 (Box 371, Folder 1-4)
    - Bellamy, Edward, 385905 (Box 372, Folder 1)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, 385906 (Box 372, Folder 2)
    - Biography, 385907 (Box 372, Folder 3)
    - Blacks, 385908 (Box 372, Folder 4)
    - Bourgin, Frank, 385909 (Box 373, Folder 1)
    - Bow ties, 385910 (Box 373, Folder 2)
    - Brandeis, Louis, 385911 (Box 373, Folder 3)
    - Britain and France articles, 385912 (Box 373, Folder 4)
    - British Labour Party, 385913 (Box 373, Folder 5)
    - Brownson, Orestes, 385914 (Box 373, Folder 6-7)
    - Buckley debate, 385915 (Box 374, Folder 1)
    - Budenz, Louis, 385916 (Box 374, Folder 2)
    - Bundy, McGeorge, 385917 (Box 374, Folder 3)
    - Butler, B. F., 385918 (Box 374, Folder 4)
    - Campaign finance, 385919 (Box 374, Folder 5)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 385920 (Box 375, Folder 1-2)
    - Century Club, 385921 (Box 375, Folder 3)
    - Century Club, 385922 (Box 376, Folder 1-2)
    - Chomsky, Noam, 385923 (Box 376, Folder 3)
    - City University of New York, 385924 (Box 376, Folder 4-7)
    - Civil War, 385925 (Box 376, Folder 8)
    - Civility, 385926 (Box 376, Folder 9)
    - Class notes, 385927
      - 1966-1977, 385928 (Box 377, Folder 1-20)
      - 1978-1982, 385929 (Box 378, Folder 1-9)
      - 1982-1988, 385930 (Box 379, Folder 1-11)
      - 1989-1993, 385931 (Box 380, Folder 1-6)
      - Reading lists, 385932 (Box 380, Folder 7)
      - Seminars, 385933 (Box 380, Folder 8-9)
    - Clinton, Bill, 385934 (Box 381, Folder 1-2)
    - Cold War, 385935 (Box 381, Folder 3-5)
    - Cold War revisionism, 385936 (Box 382, Folder 1)
    - Columbus, Christopher, 385937 (Box 382, Folder 2)
    - Committee in Defense of History, 385938 (Box 382, Folder 3)
    - Communist Party, 385939 (Box 382, Folder 4-6)
    - Communist Party, 385940 (Box 383, Folder 1-2)
    - Compulsory godliness, 385941 (Box 383, Folder 3)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 385942 (Box 383, Folder 4-6)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 385943 (Box 384, Folder 1-2)
    - Constitution, 385944 (Box 384, Folder 3)
    - Croly, Herbert, 385945 (Box 384, Folder 4)
    - Cuba, 385946 (Box 385, Folder 1)
    - Cuban Missile Crisis, 385947 (Box 385, Folder 2-3)
    - Cultural imperialism, 385948 (Box 385, Folder 4)
    - Culture, 385949 (Box 385, Folder 5)
    - Currie, Lauchlin, 385950 (Box 386, Folder 1)
    - Cycles of American History, 385951 (Box 386, Folder 2-4)
    - Davies, Joe, 385952 (Box 387, Folder 1)
    - Deaths, 385953 (Box 387, Folder 2)
    - Democracy, 385954 (Box 387, Folder 3)
    - Democratic Convention, 1972; 385955 (Box 387, Folder 4)
    - Democratic Party, 385956 (Box 387, Folder 5)
    - Dewey, John, 385957 (Box 387, Folder 6)
    - Diplomatic history, 385958 (Box 387, Folder 7)
    - Dissent, 385959 (Box 388, Folder 1)
    - Disuniting of America, 385960 (Box 388, Folder 2-3)
    - Dulles, Allen, 385961 (Box 388, Folder 4)
    - Dunne, Finley Peter, 385962 (Box 388, Folder 5)
    - Dworkin, Ronald, 385963 (Box 388, Folder 6)
    - Dynasties, 385964 (Box 388, Folder 7)
    - Education, 385965 (Box 389, Folder 1)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 385966 (Box 389, Folder 2)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt Institute, 385967 (Box 389, Folder 3)
    - Electoral College, 385968 (Box 389, Folder 4-5)
    - Electronics, 385969 (Box 389, Folder 6)
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 385970 (Box 389, Folder 7)
    - Encounter, 385971 (Box 389, Folder 8)
    - English-Speaking Union, 385972 (Box 389, Folder 9)
    - Evolution of American Thought, 385973 (Box 389, Folder 10-13)
    - Executive privilege, 385974 (Box 389, Folder 14)
    - Face the Nation, 385975 (Box 389, Folder 15)
    - Fair Deal, 385976 (Box 389, Folder 16)
    - Fairbank, John K., 385977 (Box 390, Folder 1)
    - Farrell, J. T., 385978 (Box 390, Folder 2)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 385979 (Box 390, Folder 3)
    - Film, 385980 (Box 390, Folder 4)
    - Finletter conference, 385981 (Box 391, Folder 1-10)
    - Foreign policy, 385982 (Box 391, Folder 11-13)
    - Foreign Service, 385983 (Box 392, Folder 1)
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Library, 385984 (Box 392, Folder 2)
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Foundation, 385985 (Box 392, Folder 3-4)
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Four Freedoms Foundation, 385986 (Box 392, Folder 5)
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Four Freedoms Foundation, 385987 (Box 393, Folder 1)
    - Franklin Mint, 385988 (Box 393, Folder 2)
    - Galbraith Fund, 385989 (Box 393, Folder 3)
    - Generations, 385990 (Box 393, Folder 4)
    - Genteel tradition, 385991 (Box 393, Folder 5)
    - Ghost writing, 385992 (Box 393, Folder 6)
    - Good Neighbor Policy, 385993 (Box 393, Folder 7)
    - Gordievsky, Oleg and Hopkins, Harry, 385994 (Box 393, Folder 8)
    - Gore, Albert Jr., 385995 (Box 393, Folder 9)
    - Government, 385996 (Box 393, Folder 10)
    - Grant, Frances, 385997 (Box 393, Folder 11)
    - Guyana, 385998 (Box 393, Folder 12)
    - Harding, Warren G., 385999 (Box 394, Folder 1)
    - Harriman, Averell, 386000 (Box 394, Folder 2-5)
    - Harriman, Pamela, 386001 (Box 395, Folder 1)
    - Harvard University, 386002 (Box 395, Folder 2-6)
    - Harvard fellow travelers, 386003 (Box 396, Folder 1)
    - Hays, Brooks, 386004 (Box 396, Folder 2)
    - Henty, G.A., 386005 (Box 396, Folder 3)
    - Hersh, Seymour, 386006 (Box 396, Folder 4)
    - Hildreth, Richard, 386007 (Box 396, Folder 5)
    - Hiss, Alger, 386008 (Box 396, Folder 6)
    - Historical forgeries, 386009 (Box 396, Folder 7)
    - History, 386010 (Box 396, Folder 8-9)
    - History, inscrutability of, 386011 (Box 397, Folder 1)
    - History and secrecy, 386012 (Box 397, Folder 2-3)
    - History of American Life, 386013 (Box 397, Folder 4-5)
    - Hofstadter, Richard, 386014 (Box 398, Folder 1)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 386015 (Box 398, Folder 2)
    - Holocaust, 386016 (Box 398, Folder 3)
    - Honorary degrees, 386017 (Box 398, Folder 4)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 386018 (Box 398, Folder 5)
    - Howells, William Dean, 386019 (Box 398, Folder 6)
    - Humphrey, Hubert, 386020 (Box 398, Folder 7)
    - The Ike Age Revisited, 386021 (Box 398, Folder 8)
    - Immigration, 386022 (Box 398, Folder 9)
    - Impeachment, 386023 (Box 398, Folder 10)
    - Impeachment, 386024 (Box 399, Folder 1-2)
    - Imperialism, 386025 (Box 399, Folder 3)
    - Institute on United Nations Studies, 386026 (Box 399, Folder 4)
    - Intellectuals, 386027 (Box 399, Folder 5-6)
    - Interposition, 386028 (Box 399, Folder 7)
    - Isolationism, 386029 (Box 399, Folder 8)
    - Isolationists, 386030 (Box 399, Folder 9)
    - Italy, 386031 (Box 400, Folder 1-2)
    - Jackson, Andrew, 386032 (Box 400, Folder 3)
    - Jackson, Robert H., 386033 (Box 400, Folder 4)
    - Jenkins, Roy, 386034 (Box 400, Folder 5)
    - John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, 386035 (Box 400, Folder 6-8)
    - Johnson, Lyndon, 386036 (Box 401, Folder 1)
    - Kazan, Elia, 386037 (Box 401, Folder 2)
    - Kennan, George, 386038 (Box 401, Folder 3)
    - Kennedy or Nixon?, 386039 (Box 401, Folder 4)
    - Kennedy, John F., 386040 (Box 401, Folder 5-9)
    - Kennedy, John F., 386041 (Box 402, Folder 1-4)
    - Kennedy, John F. papers, folder 1 of 2, 386042 (Box 402, Folder 5)
      Related to Kennedy's presidential papers
    - Kennedy, John F. papers, folder 2 of 2, 386043 (Box 403, Folder 1)
    - Kennedy, John F. tapes, 386044 (Box 403, Folder 2)
    - Kennedy, John F. and Robert F., 386045 (Box 403, Folder 3)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 386046 (Box 403, Folder 4)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 386047 (Box 404, Folder 1-9)
    - Kennedys, 386048 (Box 405, Folder 1)
    - Koestler, Arthur, 386049 (Box 405, Folder 2)
    - Korea, 386050 (Box 405, Folder 3)
    - Korean War, 386051 (Box 405, Folder 4)
    - Latin America, 386052 (Box 405, Folder 5)
    - Liberal Democracy, 386053 (Box 405, Folder 6)
    - Liberalism, 386054 (Box 405, Folder 7-8)
    - Libraries, 386055 (Box 407, Folder 1)
    - Life in the 20th Century, 386056 (Box 407, Folder 2)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 386057 (Box 407, Folder 3-4)
    - Literary pals, 386058 (Box 407, Folder 5)
    - Little, Brown & Co., 386059 (Box 407, Folder 6)
    - Lovett, Robert interview, 386060 (Box 408, Folder 1)
    - Loyalty, 386061 (Box 408, Folder 2-3)
    - Manifest Destiny, 386062 (Box 408, Folder 4)
    - Marshall Plan, 386063 (Box 408, Folder 5)
    - Martha's Vineyard, 386064 (Box 408, Folder 6)
    - McCarthy, Joseph, 386065 (Box 408, Folder 7-8)
    - McCarthy, Mary, 386066 (Box 408, Folder 9)
    - McGovern, George, 386067 (Box 408, Folder 10)
    - McGovern campaigns, 386068
      - Presidential, 386069 (Box 409, Folder 1-4)
      - Senatorial, 386070 (Box 410, Folder 1)
    - Mencken, H.L., 386071 (Box 410, Folder 2)
    - Military mind, 386072 (Box 410, Folder 3)
    - Millennium, 386073 (Box 410, Folder 4)
    - Modern Library, 386074 (Box 410, Folder 5-6)
    - Mount Auburn Cemetery, 386075 (Box 411, Folder 1)
    - Multiculturalism, 386076 (Box 411, Folder 2-4)
    - National emergency, 386077 (Box 411, Folder 5)
    - National Historical and Public Records Commission, 386078 (Box 412, Folder 1)
    - National History Standards, 386079 (Box 412, Folder 2-3)
    - National interest, 386080 (Box 413, Folder 1)
    - Nationalism, 386081 (Box 413, Folder 2)
    - Neo-isolationism, 386082 (Box 413, Folder 3)
    - New conservatism, 386083 (Box 413, Folder 4)
    - New left, 386084 (Box 413, Folder 5)
    - New politics, 386085 (Box 413, Folder 6)
    - New York Public Library, 386086 (Box 413, Folder 7)
    - Newseum, 386087 (Box 413, Folder 8)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 386088 (Box 414, Folder 1-6)
    - Nineteen fifties, 386089 (Box 415, Folder 1)
      Time period as subject; not all material dates from these years
    - Nineteen fifty-two, 386090 (Box 415, Folder 2)
      Time period as subject
    - Nineteen fifty-four, 386091 (Box 415, Folder 3)
    - Nixon, Richard M., 386092 (Box 415, Folder 4)
    - Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 386093 (Box 415, Folder 5-7)
    - Open Door policy, 386094 (Box 415, Folder 8)
    - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 386095 (Box 416, Folder 1)
    - Partisan Review, 386096 (Box 416, Folder 2)
    - Pearl Harbor, 386097 (Box 416, Folder 3)
    - Perkins, Frances, 386098 (Box 416, Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia Bulletin Forum, 386099 (Box 416, Folder 5)
    - Pledge of allegiance, 386100 (Box 416, Folder 6)
    - Political correctness, 386101 (Box 416, Folder 7)
    - Political novel, 386102 (Box 416, Folder 8)
    - Politics, 386103 (Box 416, Folder 9)
    - Popular ignorance, 386104 (Box 416, Folder 10)
    - Presidency, 386105 (Box 417, Folder 1-6)
    - Presidency, 386106 (Box 418, Folder 1)
    - Presidency and foreign policy, 386107 (Box 418, Folder 2)
    - Presidential conventions, 386108 (Box 418, Folder 3)
    - Presidential campaigns, 386109
      - 1952, 386110 (Box 418, Folder 4)
      - 1952, 386111 (Box 419, Folder 1-2)
      - 1960, 386112 (Box 419, Folder 3)
      - 1968, 386113 (Box 419, Folder 4-6)
      - 1972, 386114 (Box 420, Folder 1)
      - 1980, 386115 (Box 420, Folder 2-5)
    - Presidential libraries, 386116 (Box 421, Folder 1)
    - Presidential papers, 386117 (Box 421, Folder 2)
    - Presidential polls, 386118 (Box 421, Folder 3-8)
    - Presidential polls, 386119 (Box 422, Folder 1-2)
    - Prichard, Edward, 386120 (Box 422, Folder 3)
    - Printers' Ink, 386121 (Box 422, Folder 4)
    - Psycho-history, 386122 (Box 422, Folder 5)
    - Puerto Rico, 386123 (Box 422, Folder 6)
    - Quotes, 386124 (Box 423, Folder 1-2)
    - Rauh, Joseph L. Jr., 386125 (Box 423, Folder 3-4)
    - Ravitch, Diane, 386126 (Box 424, Folder 1)
    - Reeves, Richard, 386127 (Box 424, Folder 2)
    - Relativism, 386128 (Box 424, Folder 3)
    - Religion, 386129 (Box 424, Folder 4-5)
    - Resignation, 386130 (Box 424, Folder 6)
    - Reviews, 386131 (Box 424, Folder 7)
    - Robert F. Kennedy Book Award, 386132 (Box 424, Folder 8-9)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 386133 (Box 425, Folder 1-2)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor oral history, 386134 (Box 425, Folder 3)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 386135 (Box 425, Folder 4)
    - Roosevelt family, 386136 (Box 425, Folder 5)
    - Salvemini, Gaetano, 386137 (Box 425, Folder 6)
    - Sanabria case, 386138 (Box 425, Folder 7)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 386139 (Box 425, Folder 8-9)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Sr., 386140 (Box 426, Folder 1)
    - Schlesinger on Schlesinger, 386141 (Box 426, Folder 2)
    - Schlesinger Library, 386142 (Box 426, Folder 3-4)
    - Schlesinger's (restaurant), 386143 (Box 426, Folder 5)
    - Schweitzer Chair, 1968-1982; 386144 (Box 427-428)
    - Security, 386145 (Box 429, Folder 1)
    - Separation of powers, 386146 (Box 429, Folder 2)
    - Smith, Jean Kennedy and Stephen, 386147 (Box 429, Folder 3-5)
    - Social lists, 386148 (Box 430, Folder 1)
    - Soviet policy, 386149 (Box 430, Folder 2)
    - Soviet Union, 386150 (Box 430, Folder 3)
    - Space, 386151 (Box 430, Folder 4)
    - Spain, 386152 (Box 431, Folder 1)
    - Stevenson, Adlai, 386153 (Box 431, Folder 2-4)
    - Stevenson, Adlai, 386154 (Box 432, Folder 1-5)
    - Strategy, 386155 (Box 432, Folder 6)
    - Supreme Court, 386156 (Box 432, Folder 7)
    - Supreme Court and the Constitution, 386157 (Box 432, Folder 8)
    - Taft, Robert, 386158 (Box 432, Folder 9)
    - Times Literary Supplement, 386159 (Box 433, Folder 1)
    - Tocqueville, Alexis de, 386160 (Box 433, Folder 2-3)
    - Travel, 386161 (Box 433, Folder 4)
    - Truman, Harry S., 386162 (Box 433, Folder 5-6)
    - Twentieth Century Fund, 386163 (Box 433, Folder 7)
    - United Nations, 386164 (Box 434, Folder 1)
    - Velocity of History, 386165 (Box 434, Folder 2)
    - Vice Presidency, 386166 (Box 434, Folder 3-5)
    - Vidal, Gore, 386167 (Box 434, Folder 6)
    - Vietnam, 386168 (Box 435, Folder 1-6)
    - Vital Center, 386169 (Box 435, Folder 7)
    - Wall Street Journal, 386170 (Box 436, Folder 1)
    - Wallace, Henry, 386171 (Box 436, Folder 2)
    - War-making power, 386172 (Box 436, Folder 3)
    - War and the American Presidency, 386173 (Box 436, Folder 4)
    - Welfare state, 386174 (Box 436, Folder 5)
    - Who's Who, 386175 (Box 436, Folder 6)
    - Wilson, Edmund and McCarthy, Mary, 386176 (Box 436, Folder 7)
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 386177 (Box 437, Folder 1)
    - World Court, 386178 (Box 437, Folder 2)
    - Yalta, 386179 (Box 437, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IV. B. Book Files, 1940s-1990s; 386180; 69 boxes
    In researching the history books he considered his life's work, Schlesinger gathered voluminous files of data in the form of published material, note cards, transcripts and annotations. In some cases, he organized his research by subject and in other instances, his research was organized by chapter. The largest amount of research in this series informed Schlesinger's three books on the career of Franklin Delano Roosevelt. Some research also seems to have been intended for the planned subsequent volumes in that series. One set of research files for the Roosevelt books is arranged alphabetically by subject, while another set is arranged numerically by section number. These section numbers range from 22 to 33; the first twenty-one sections were not received with the collection. The other large section of book-related research in this subseries relates to xxRobert Kennedy and His Timesxx. Among the other research for that work are a great many oral histories from those who knew and worked with Robert Kennedy, some conducted by Schlesinger himself and others obtained by Schlesinger from other sources. Selected pages of the oral histories have been classified for national security reasons and may be declassified on a case-by-case basis over time. Also of note here are Schlesinger's original note cards for xxThe Age of Jacksonxx, his first major success.
    - Age of Roosevelt, 386181
      - Subjects, 386182
        - Agrarian radicalism, 386183 (Box 438, Folder 1)
        - Agricultural Adjustment Administration (AAA), 386184 (Box 438, Folder 2)
        - AAA fight, 386185 (Box 438, Folder 3)
        - Agricultural policy, 386186 (Box 438, Folder 4-5)
        - Agricultural unrest, 386187 (Box 438, Folder 6)
        - Agriculture--wartime, 386188 (Box 438, Folder 7)
        - Aid to Allies, 386189 (Box 438, Folder 8)
        - Alienation of business, 386190 (Box 438, Folder 9)
        - Anschluss, 386191 (Box 438, Folder 10)
        - Anti-Communism, 386192 (Box 438, Folder 11)
        - Anti-Nazi, 386193 (Box 439, Folder 1)
        - Anti-Nazi Germans, 386194 (Box 439, Folder 2)
        - Anti-Nazi refugees, 386195 (Box 439, Folder 3)
        - Anti-New Deal, 386196 (Box 439, Folder 4)
        - Anti-Semitism, 386197 (Box 439, Folder 5)
        - Antitrust policy, 386198 (Box 439, Folder 6)
        - Anti-war, 386199 (Box 439, Folder 7)
        - Appeasement, 386200 (Box 439, Folder 8)
        - Army-Navy, 386201 (Box 439, Folder 9)
        - Atlantic Charter, 386202 (Box 439, Folder 10)
        - Atomic bomb, 386203 (Box 439, Folder 11)
        - Australian and New Zealand Army Corps, 386204 (Box 440, Folder 1)
        - Axis, 386205 (Box 440, Folder 2)
        - Balkan invasion, 386206 (Box 440, Folder 3)
        - Big Three conferences, 386207 (Box 440, Folder 4)
        - Bombing--European Theater of Operations, 386208 (Box 440, Folder 5)
        - Bonus March, 386209 (Box 440, Folder 6)
        - Brain trust, 386210 (Box 440, Folder 7)
        - Budgetary control over S.P.A., 386211 (Box 440, Folder 8)
        - Buenos Aires, 386212 (Box 440, Folder 9)
        - Business and foreign policy, 386213 (Box 440, Folder 10)
        - Business philosophy, 386214 (Box 440, Folder 11)
        - Business, pro-New Deal, 386215 (Box 440, Folder 12)
        - Business reaction, 386216 (Box 440, Folder 13)
        - Business, war, 386217 (Box 440, Folder 14)
        - Cabinet reorganization, 386218 (Box 441, Folder 1)
        - Cairo/Teheran, 386219 (Box 441, Folder 2)
        - Campobello, 386220 (Box 441, Folder 3)
        - Canada, 386221 (Box 441, Folder 4)
        - Casablanca, 386222 (Box 441, Folder 5)
        - Catholic bloc, 386223 (Box 441, Folder 6)
        - Catholics, 386224 (Box 441, Folder 7)
        - Chicago convention, 386225 (Box 441, Folder 8)
        - China, 386226 (Box 442, Folder 1-4)
        - Chronology, 386227 (Box 442, Folder 5)
        - Churchill, Winston, 386228 (Box 442, Folder 6-7)
        - Civil liberties, 386229 (Box 442, Folder 8-9)
        - Civil rights, 386230 (Box 443, Folder 1-3)
        - Cohen, Benjamin and Corcoran, Thomas, 386231 (Box 443, Folder 4)
        - Cold War, 386232 (Box 443, Folder 5)
        - Collaboration/resistance, 386233 (Box 443, Folder 6)
        - Communist Party, 386234 (Box 443, Folder 7-10)
        - Congress, 386235 (Box 444, Folder 1-2)
        - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO), 386236 (Box 444, Folder 3)
        - Conservation, 386237 (Box 444, Folder 4-5)
        - Construction, 386238 (Box 444, Folder 6)
        - Coolidge, Calvin, 386239 (Box 444, Folder 7)
        - Coughlin, Father Charles, 386240 (Box 444, Folder 8)
        - Coy, Wayne, 386241 (Box 444, Folder 9)
        - Crash (1929), 386242 (Box 444, Folder 10)
        - Crisis of 1932, 386243 (Box 444, Folder 11)
        - Cultural problems, 386244 (Box 444, Folder 12)
        - Curtiss-Wright case, 386245 (Box 444, Folder 13)
        - D-Day and after, 386246 (Box 445, Folder 1)
        - Demagogues, 386247 (Box 445, Folder 2)
        - Demand for planning, 386248 (Box 445, Folder 3)
        - Democracy's future, 386249 (Box 445, Folder 4)
        - Democratic Party, 386250 (Box 445, Folder 5-7)
        - Despair, 386251 (Box 445, Folder 8)
        - Destroyer deal, 386252 (Box 445, Folder 9)
        - Dies Committee, 386253 (Box 446, Folder 1)
        - Diplomacy, 386254 (Box 446, Folder 2)
        - Disarmament, 386255 (Box 446, Folder 3-4)
        - Draft, 386256 (Box 446, Folder 5)
        - Economic aid/Fascism, 386257 (Box 446, Folder 6)
        - Economic motives, 386258 (Box 446, Folder 7)
        - Economic nationalism, 386259 (Box 446, Folder 8)
        - Economic warfare, 386260 (Box 446, Folder 9)
        - Ethiopia, 386261 (Box 446, Folder 10-11)
        - Ethnic politics, 386262 (Box 446, Folder 12)
        - Europe (Hitler/Mussolini), 386263 (Box 446, Folder 13)
        - European reaction to the New Deal, 386264 (Box 446, Folder 14)
        - European resistance, 386265 (Box 446, Folder 15)
        - Exile governments, 386266 (Box 446, Folder 16)
        - Far Eastern policy, 1932-1940; 386267 (Box 447, Folder 1-3)
        - Farm holiday, 386268 (Box 447, Folder 4)
        - Fascism, 386269 (Box 447, Folder 5-7)
        - Fascist movements (U.S., U.K.), 386270 (Box 448, Folder 1)
        - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 386271 (Box 448, Folder 2)
        - Finland, 386272 (Box 448, Folder 3)
        - Foreign correspondents, 386273 (Box 448, Folder 4)
        - Foreign policy, 386274
          - 1920s-1930s, 386275 (Box 448, Folder 5-9)
          - General, 386276 (Box 449, Folder 1)
        - France, 386277 (Box 449, Folder 2)
        - Franco, Francisco, 386278 (Box 449, Folder 3)
        - Frankfurter, Felix, 386279 (Box 449, Folder 4)
        - Garner, John Nance, 386280 (Box 449, Folder 5)
        - G.I. War, 386281 (Box 449, Folder 6)
        - German policy, 386282 (Box 449, Folder 7)
        - Gold stabilization, 386283 (Box 449, Folder 8)
        - Good Neighbor policy, 386284 (Box 450, Folder 1)
        - Government reorganization, 386285 (Box 450, Folder 2)
        - Governorship, 386286 (Box 450, Folder 3)
        - Grassroots radicalism, 386287 (Box 450, Folder 4)
        - Great Debate, 386288 (Box 450, Folder 5)
        - Greece, 386289 (Box 450, Folder 6)
        - Harding, Warren G., 386290 (Box 451, Folder 1)
        - Health, 386291 (Box 451, Folder 2)
        - Historical fiction, 386292 (Box 451, Folder 3)
        - Hitler, Adolf, 386293 (Box 451, Folder 4-6)
        - Holocaust, 386294 (Box 451, Folder 7-9)
        - Home front, 386295 (Box 451, Folder 10)
        - Hoover, Herbert, 386296
          - 1920s, 386297 (Box 451, Folder 11)
          - Depression, 386298 (Box 451, Folder 12)
          - Foreign policy, 386299 (Box 452, Folder 1)
          - General, 386300 (Box 452, Folder 2)
        - Hopkins, Harry, 386301 (Box 452, Folder 3)
        - Howe, Louis, 386302 (Box 452, Folder 4)
        - Hull, Cordell and Welles, Sumner, 386303 (Box 452, Folder 5)